so
i've been reading nishitani
one of the japanese philosophers from
the kyoto school
and man when i read him i
i think i feel the most like an american
it's like the american trying to
understand
this concept of well not the the the
non-concept of emptiness
or nothing
is so slippery right when i think i got
it i'm like oh yeah
like i finally get it the nothing the
empty the
and then i said like my next thought
will be like yeah i bet i can like
turn a profit on this or something
however something is i think kind of
slipping through the cracks in a good
way
you know in this in this kind of
contemplation
and
what i would say seems like the east
really has
um for a very long time
a deep deep intuition about okay
and it's the sense of emptiness is
one of the one of the parts about
the understanding of emptiness
is it's not like something right
that that isn't therefore it's nothing
it's not the absence of something
emptiness is form and form is emptiness
so there's this
there's this place in which
[Music]
that rock there
in its rock hood is precisely
nut rock
it's very paradoxical in some sense but
yet there's a way in which i'm
if we can understand it
it's one of those things that become
really really obvious
like it's been obvious the whole time in
fact you're
you're not understanding it
was predicated on it even you're not
understanding
emptiness was in some sense made
possible by
the emptiness
so in one sense as i sit here right i'm
looking at the
at the water and if we look at it like
this it's like
if we say that the
we say that the water
is space
and let's say that the waves
or time
and if we say that the pattern
upon which the waves
time and the water space
the pattern that that makes is knowledge
so right now the the water
is space
the waves time
the patterns that time makes in space
is knowledge
he's oh of the weirdest
you